Guide to the Anthony Taussig collection of English legal manuscripts
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Anthony Taussig collection of English legal manuscripts
1280-1956
OSB MSS 184
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
48.29
(73 boxes)
A collection of approximately 400 manuscript items, including letters; letterbooks; copies of statutes, pleadings, opinions and precedents; King's Bench reports; abridgments and commonplace books of cases; and other papers, documenting the development and practice of English law and the evolution of the English legal system from the thirteenth into the twentieth century. Included are an early copy of Henry de Bracton's De legibus Anglie; a fourteenth-century pocket compilation of "Statuta vetera" that opens with a copy of the Magna Carta; case reports from the sixteenth through the nineteenth centuries; letters, opinions and notes by a range of English legal figures, including William Blackstone, Edward Coke, Edward Law, Lord Thurlow, and Francis Wedderburn; and guides to court proceedings and practice from the seventeenth and eighteenth centuries.
Taussig, Anthony
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Purchased from Anthony Taussig on the Hazel M. Osborn and the James Marshall and Marie-Louise Osborn Funds, 2012.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Scope and Contents
A collection of approximately 400 manuscript items, including letters; letterbooks; copies of statutes, pleadings, opinions and precedents; King's Bench reports; abridgments and commonplace books of cases; and other papers, documenting the development and practice of English law and the evolution of the English legal system from the thirteenth into the twentieth century. Included are an early copy of Henry de Bracton's De legibus Anglie; a fourteenth-century pocket compilation of "Statuta vetera" that opens with a copy of the Magna Carta; case reports from the sixteenth through the nineteenth centuries; letters, opinions and notes by a range of English legal figures, including William Blackstone, Edward Coke, Edward Law, Lord Thurlow, and Francis Wedderburn; and guides to court proceedings and practice from the seventeenth and eighteenth centuries.
In addition, the collection contains a letterbook of Wiliam Tidd; papers of Sir Michael Foster and his heirs, including correspondence related to the Corn Riots of 1753 and Foster's work on habeas corpus; and correspondence and other documentation related to the operation of the Poor Laws in England.
Arrangement
Arranged by Taussig catalog number as assigned in A Catalogue of the Legal Manuscripts of Anthony Taussig.
Magna carta -- Early works to 1800; Forms (Law) -- Great Britain -- Early works to 1800; Law -- England; Law -- England -- Early works to 1800; Law -- England -- Sources; Law -- Great Britain; Law -- Great Britain -- Early works to 1800; Law -- Great Britain -- Sources; Law -- Interpretation and construction; Law -- Interpretation and construction -- Early works to 1800; Poor laws -- Great Britain; Poor laws -- Great Britain -- Early works to 1800; Statutes -- Great Britain; Blackstone, William, 1723-1780; Bracton, Henry de, -1268; Coke, Edward, Sir, 1552-1634; Foster, Michael, Sir, 1689-1763; Maitland, Frederic William, 1850-1906; Taussig, Anthony; Thurlow, Edward Thurlow, Baron, 1731-1806; Tidd, William, 1760-1847; Rosslyn, Alexander Wedderburn, Earl of, 1733-1805
- Taussig Catalog # 1: Bradley, Practical points in conveyancing 1820 (printed), interleaved and annotated [77.9.26 Wildy] (Box 1)
- Taussig Catalog # 1.1: 17th cent. (c. 1620/30) MS version of part of treatise on nobility by William Bird, 44 ff., printed as Judge Dodderidge, His law of nobility 1658 [77.10.5 Alan Thomas] (Box 1)
- Taussig Catalog # 2: c. 1750-1850 file of poor law papers, some printed, some MS [80.2.16 Hodgkins] (Box 1)
- Taussig Catalog # 3: 14th cent. statuta vetera, 198 ff. [81.7.14 Sotheby's]
- Taussig Catalog # 4.1-4.2: Euer doctrina placitandi, 2 vols., 1677 (printed), interleaved with 18th cent. MS annotations by [?]Joseph Yates [81.9.26 M. Solomon's], 2 (Box 1)
- Taussig Catalog # 5: 17th cent. (beginning and c. 1650) MS abridgment of cases and practice notes by William Style, 257 ff. [81.10.27 Sotheby's] (Box 2)
- Taussig Catalog # 6: 17th cent. MS reports of cases 1611-14, 63 ff., belonged to William Style [81.10.27 Sotheby's] (Box 2)
- Taussig Catalog # 7: 16th cent. (end) MS reports of cases 1586-93 and 1585-90, 169 ff., belonged to William Style [81.10.27 Sotheby's] (Box 2)
- Taussig Catalog # 8: 17th cent. (c. 1630/40) MS entries, ii + 286 pp. [81.10.27 Sotheby's] (Box 2)
- Taussig Catalog # 9: 18th cent. (c. 1702) MS notes on pleading, 280 pp. [81.12.4 Bristow] (Box 2)
- Taussig Catalog # 10: 18th cent. (1727) appointment by judges of agent to receive fees for writs of dedimus potestatem, s. sh. fo. [81.12.10 Phillips] (Box 2)
- Taussig Catalog # 11: 14th cent. (early) MS of Britton, 66 ff. (lacking many leaves) [82.3.6. Alan Thomas, ex Sotheby's 79.12.11]
- Taussig Catalog # 12: 16th cent. MS readings on statutes, 79 ff. [82.5.5 Christie's] (Box 2)
- Taussig Catalog # 13: 17th cent. (c. 1640) MS, judicial writs, 262 pp. [82.5.5 Christie's] (Box 2)
- Taussig Catalog # 14: 18th cent. (first quarter) MS Comyns' Digest, 227 ff. (first part only) [82.5.29 East End warehouse] (Box 2)
- Taussig Catalog # 15: 17th cent. (c. 1630) MS Wentworth on Executors, 97 ff. (printed 1641, about half of printed text missing) [82.7.8 Bristow] (Box 3)
- Taussig Catalog # 16: 17th cent. MS description of office of alnager, 1 p. [82.9.22 F. Edwards] (Box 3)
- Taussig Catalog # 17: c. 1822 ALS Brougham to Zachary Macaulay (Misc. 72) [82.9.22 F. Edwards] (Box 3)
- Taussig Catalog # 18: 19th cent. (1802) MS law library catalogue, i + 30 pp. [82.10.25 Grinke] (Box 3)
- Taussig Catalog # 19: 13th cent. Bracton, lacking many leaves [82.12.7 Sotheby's]
- Taussig Catalog # 20: 18th cent. (c. 1810) MS House of Lords standing orders, 76 ff. [83.2.4 Christie's] (Box 3)
- Taussig Catalog # 21: 17th cent. (c. 1695/1700) MSS seven charges to Quarter Sessions, each in pamphlet [83.3.8 Bristow] (Box 3)
- Taussig Catalog # 22: 18th cent. (1717-18) MS index to proceedings of House of Lords etc., 555 pp. [83.5.6 Chistie's] (Box 4 (Oversize))
- Taussig Catalog # 23: 18th cent. MS commonplace book, including abridgment of Puffendorf's Law of nature and nations, c. 180 ff. [83.3.12 P. Eaton] (Box 3)
- Taussig Catalog # 24: 1832 ALS J.J. Park to Sir Francis Palgrave (Misc. 86) [83.5.17(b) Block] (Box 3)
- Taussig Catalog # 25: 1867 ALS Sir John Rolt to Lord St. Leonards (Misc. 107) [83.5.17(c) Block] (Box 3)
- Taussig Catalog # 26: 1925/1928 two ALS and one typed letter Lord Birkenhead to Lady Cave (Misc. 121) (Box 3)
- Taussig Catalog # 28: Townesend Tables 1667 (printed), interleaved and annotated [83.11.2 Bennett], 2 (Box 3)
- Taussig Catalog # 29: 17th cent. MS miscellanea concerning courts, group of c. 24 legal pamphlets bound together, 365 ff. [83.11.8 Sotheby's] (Box 5)
- Taussig Catalog # 30: Laws respecting landlords, tenants and lodgersc. 1827 (printed), interleaved with annotations [84.2.2 Wildy] (Box 5)
- Taussig Catalog # 31: 19th cent. (1834) MS law library catalogue, 122 ff. [81.2.27 Professional Books] (Box 5)
- Taussig Catalog # 32: 18th cent. (c. 1770) MS House of Lords standing orders, 86 ff. [84.3.6(a) Blackwell] (Box 5)
- Taussig Catalog # 33: 1815 ALS from Michael Nolan giving legal advice (Misc. 59) [84.3.6(b) Bristow] (Box 5)
- Taussig Catalog # 34: 17th cent. (c. 1700) abridgment relating to estates in land, 544 pp. [84.3.20 Sotheby's] (Box 5)
- Taussig Catalog # 35: 17th cent. (c. 1661) MS exchequer orders, 47 pp. [84.5.10 Bristow] (Box 5)
- Taussig Catalog # 36: Littleton Tenures 1604 (printed), interleaved and annotated [84.8.16 Taviners] (Box 5)
- Taussig Catalog # 37: The Parish Officer (c. 1819) (printed), interleaved and with MS notes on poor law [84.8.29 Wildy] (Box 5)
- Taussig Catalog # 38: 17th cent. MS precedents for justice of peace and notes on tithes, 61 pp. [84.9.17 Bristow] (Box 5)
- Taussig Catalog # 39: 17th cent. (1675) MS call of serjeants under sign manual of Charles II, s. sh. [84.9.19(a) Christie's] (Box 6)
- Taussig Catalog # 40: 17th cent. (1675) MS appointment of King's Serjeant under sign manual of Charles II, s. sh. [84.9.19(b) Christie's] (Box 6)
- Taussig Catalog # 41: 18th cent. (2nd half) MS account book of Clement's Inn 1757-1785, 307 pp. [84.9.19(c) Christie's] (Box 6)
- Taussig Catalog # 42: 17th cent. (1st half) MS epitome of Fitzherbert's Natura brevium, 253 ff. [84.10.17 Bristow] (Box 6)
- Taussig Catalog # 43: 17th cent. MS proposals for relief of orphans in City of London, 2 sh. [84.11.1(a) Mayfly] (Box 6)
- Taussig Catalog # 44: Chamberlain R., Complete Justice 1681 (printed), interleaved and annotated [85.1.29 Solomon's] (Box 6)
- Taussig Catalog # 45.1-45.2: 19th cent. MS Butler C., Practical Observations on Conveyancing, 2 vols., 138 + 142 ff. [85.2.27 Bloobsbury Book Auctions], 2 (Box 6)
- Taussig Catalog # 46: 18th cent. MS abridgment of Coke's Reports, 31 ff. [85.3.1 Stride & Son] (Box 6)
- Taussig Catalog # 47.1: Coke, Reports (17th cent., various dates), 11 vols. (printed), with annotations, vol. 1 [85.3.26 Phillips Sherborne] (Box 6)
- Taussig Catalog # 47.2-47.11: Coke, Reports (17th cent., various dates), 11 vols. (printed), with annotations, vols. 2-11 [85.3.26 Phillips Sherborne], 10 (Box 7)
- Taussig Catalog # 48: 17th cent. (1661/2) MS authority to pay G. Sweet as professor of civil law, s. sh. [85.4.17 Maggs] (Box 8)
- Taussig Catalog # 49: 19th cent. (1832) MS order for judges' circuits under sign manual of William IV, s. sh. [85.4.22 Bristow] (Box 8)
- Taussig Catalog # 50: 16th cent (1572-86) MS court-book of manor of Treyford, Susses
  Immediate Source of Acquisition
  This manuscript was not acquired.
- Taussig Catalog # 51: 18th cent. (c. 1710-30) MS collection of opinions of counsel, 235 ff. [85.6.16 Mayfly] (Box 8)
- Taussig Catalog # 52: 17th cent. (1st half) MS Finch's Law, 256 ff. [85.6.28(a) Bloomsbury Book Auctions] (Box 8)
- Taussig Catalog # 53: 18th cent. (c. 1535) MS precedents from Durham 352 ff. [85.6.28(b) Bloomsbury Book Auctions] (Box 8)
- Taussig Catalog # 54: 18th cent. (c. 1770) MS guide to practice of House of Lords iv + 182 pp. [85.7.1 Robertshaw] (Box 8)
- Taussig Catalog # 55: 17th cent. (c. 1630) MS commonplace on the prerogative, 167 ff. [85.10.7 Maggs] (Box 8)
- Taussig Catalog # 56: 1879 ALS from Lord Justice Bramwell to Mr. Justice Huddleston (Misc. 112) [85.10.10(b) Bristow] (Box 8)
- Taussig Catalog # 57: 18th cent. (c. 1702) MS legal commonplace, 2 vols., vol. 1., 536 pp. [85.10.27 Spake] (Box 9 (Oversize))
- Taussig Catalog # 58: 16th cent. (end) MS forms of judicial writs etc., 240 ff. [85.11.1.(a) Stride & Son] (Box 8)
- Taussig Catalog # 59: 16th cent. (c. 1587) MS entries of pleadings, 218 ff. [85.11.1(b) Stride & Son] (Box 10)
- Taussig Catalog # 60: 17th cent. (early) MS entries of pleadings, 331 pp. [85.11.1(c) Stride & Son] (Box 10)
- Taussig Catalog # 61: 16th-17th cents Court rolls of Fyning Sussex 1537-9 and later [85.11.1 (d) Stride & Son]
- Taussig Catalog # 62: 19th cent. (c. 1800-1840) MSS William Tidd's letterbook, 207 letters, Tidd 1-207 [85.12.7 J. Browning ex Christie's 12.4.85], 2 (Box 10)
- Taussig Catalog # 63: 18th cent. (c. 1770) MS notes of cases on corporations by Sir Joseph Yates, 112 pp. [85.12.20 Wildy] (Box 10)
- Taussig Catalog # 64: 18th cent. Magna Carta 1680 (printed), interleaved and annotated [86.1.14 Robert Rubin] (Box 10)
- Taussig Catalog # 65: 17th cent. (1692) and 18th cent. (1701) MSS warrants to receive judges' salaries, 2 s. sh. [86.3.25 Nolan] (Box 10)
- Taussig Catalog # 66: 18th cent. (c. 1730) MS report of Mrs. Talbot's case, 6 pp. [86.6.15 ephemera dealer] (Box 10)
- Taussig Catalog # 67: 18th cent. (c. 1730) MS table of equity cases in Parliament, 190 ff. [86.6.20(a) Bloomsbury Book Auctions] (Box 10)
- Taussig Catalog # 68: 17th-18th cent. MSS collection of pleadings, 105 ff. [86.6.20(b) Bloomsbury Book Auctions] (Box 11 (Oversize))
- Taussig Catalog # 69: 15th cent. (mid) MS Natura brevium, old tenures, register of writs, 420 pp. [86.6.25 Christie's]
- Taussig Catalog # 70: 19th cent. MS notebook of Lord Brougham sitting as L.C., 465 pp. [86.8.1 Christie's] (Box 12)
- Taussig Catalog # 71: 19th cent. (c. 1810) MS copies of bills in Chancery and opinions, 148 ff. [86.9.5 Christie's] (Box 12)
- Taussig Catalog # 72: 16th cent. (1523) MS lay subsidy roll for part of Hampshire [86.11.5 Bristow] (Box 12)
- Taussig Catalog # 73: 19th cent. (1819) MS Butler C., lectures in conveyancing, 172 ff. [86.11.13(a) Bloomsbury Book Auctions] (Box 12)
- Taussig Catalog # 74: 17th cent. (first half) MS charge to grand jury and commonplace, 43 ff. [86.11.13(b) Bloomsbury Book Auctions] (Box 12)
- Taussig Catalog # 75: 17th cent. (c. 1663) MS conveyancing precedents, 24 ff. [87.1.12 David Vine] (Box 12)
- Taussig Catalog # 76: 18th cent. MSS two charges to grand juries, 3 + 3 pp. [87.6.10 Bristow] (Box 12)
- Taussig Catalog # 77: 18th cent. MS notebook of cases and statutes concerning settlement of poor, 113 ff. [87.6.18 Taviners] (Box 12)
- Taussig Catalog # 78: 1900 (2 Dec.) ALS from F.W. Maitland to editor of Juridical Review (Misc. 117) [87.6.29 Verbeke] (Box 12)
- Taussig Catalog # 78.1: Field Analysis of Blackstone's Commentaries (c. 1811) (printed), interleaved and annotated with answers to printed questions [87.7.19 Robertshaw] (Box 12)
- 18th cent. three groups of papers relating to Michael Foster/Michael Dodson/Ward, [(1) 87.10.11, (2) 87.10.21, (3) 87.1121 Spake], all MSS F1-F143 except F51-2 [cat. 173] and F40-44 [cat. 178], cf. cat. 125 and 131:
  - Taussig Catalog # 79.1-79.2: (1) F1-4, printed books with annotations by Foster including Hale Pleas of Crown 1682 and 1716 and MS draft of Discourses II and III; (2) F5-7, two MS student notebooks, 2 (Box 13 (Oversize))
  - Taussig Catalog # 79.3-79.4: (3) F7-61, correspondence and other papers of Foster (1723-45); (4) F62-7, bills relating to Foster's appointment as judge (1745), 2 (Box 14 (Oversize))
  - Taussig Catalog # 79.5-79.8: (5) F68-80, MSS of Foster relating to turnpike riots of 1749, (6) F81-97, MSS of Foster relating to corn riots of 1753; (7) F98-114, MSS of Foster relating to habeas corpus and other matters 1758-62; (8) F115-138, MSS relating to Michael Dodson 1758-95, 2 (Box 15 (Oversize))
  - Taussig Catalog # 79.9-79.18: (9) F120-143, MSS relating to John Ward 1777-1804 and (10) genealogical collections relating to Foster and his family, 10 (Box 16)
- Taussig Catalog # 80: 18th cent. MS notes of settlement cases 1756-59, 180 pp. [87.11.9 M.Hosking] (Box 17)
- Taussig Catalog # 81: 17th cent. (1625/8) MS copy of bill in Chancery 6 ff. [88.2.1(a) Spake] (Box 17)
- Taussig Catalog # 82: 18th cent. MS notes of Old Bailey procedure and cases, 104 pp. [88.2.1(b) Spake] (Box 17)
- Taussig Catalog # 83: 18th cent. MS conveyancing precedents, 66 pp. [88.2.1(a) i.e., (c) Block] (Box 17)
- Taussig Catalog # 84: Court roll of Sunnywell and Bayworth 1631 [88.2.1 (b) i.e. (d) Block]
- Taussig Catalog # 85: Customs of Manor of Harrow 1607 30pp [88.2.5 Spake]
- Taussig Catalog # 86: 18th cent. (1771-2) MS group of c. 49 letters from Hereford attorney to London agent [88.2.18 Lawrence, Crewkerne] (Box 17)
- Taussig Catalog # 87: 19th cent. (c. 1810) MS poem "The Sunday before the Assizes," 5 Aug. 1810, 4 pp. [88.2.23 Spake] (Box 17)
- Taussig Catalog # 88: Page W., Three early assize rolls for the County of Northampton 1891 (printed), with some annotations by F.W. Maitland [88.2.29 Waterfield] (Box 17)
- Taussig Catalog # 89: 17th cent. (c. 1610) MS legal commonplace, 379 ff. [88.4.21(a) Chaucer Head] (Box 17)
- Taussig Catalog # 90: Littleton, Tenures 1617 (printed), extra-marginated, interleaved and annotated [88.4.21(b) Chaucer Head] (Box 17)
- Taussig Catalog # 91: Magna Carta, cum statutis 1608 (printed), extra-marginated and annotated [88.5.25 Sotheby's] (Box 18)
- Taussig Catalog # 92: 18th cent. (1746-7) MS memoranda by attorney of documents, 13 ff. [88.6.6(a) Block] (Box 18)
- Taussig Catalog # 93: 18th cent. (c. 1737) MS letters and drafts re: conveyancing dispute (Misc. 21) [88.6.6(b) Block] (Box 18)
- Taussig Catalog # 94: 1815-20 four ALS from William Garrow to Viscount Sidmouth and Henry Hobhouse (Misc. 62) [88.6.11 Spake] (Box 18)
- Taussig Catalog # 95: 18th cent. MS collection of c. 20 orders signed by judges [88.6.19(a) Spake] (Box 19 (Oversize))
- Taussig Catalog # 96: 1734 (14 Apr.) ALS from Sir Lawrence Carter to unnamed correspondent (Misc. 20) [88.6.19(b) Spake] (Box 18)
- Taussig Catalog # 97: 1804 (27 Mar. and 20 June) two ALS letters of reference for a barrister from Sir Archibald Macdonald and Sir Nash Grose (Misc. 49) [88.6.19(c) Spake] (Box 18)
- Taussig Catalog # 98: 18th cent. (13 Sep. 1988) MS Case with opinion of James Mansfield [88.6.19(d) Spake] (Box 18)
- Taussig Catalog # 99: 18th cent. MS part of opinion of William Hawkins [88.6.19(e) Spake] (Box 18)
- Taussig Catalog # 100: 19th cent. (c. 1830) two ALS from James Scarlett to J. Wright (Misc. 81) [88.6.19(e) Spake] (Box 18)
- Taussig Catalog # 101: 1818 (27 Nov.) ALS from J.A. Murray of Scottish bar to unnamed correspondent (Misc. 68) [88.6.19(g) Spake] (Box 18)
- Taussig Catalog # 101.1: 18th cent. (1738) MS case to and opinion of Thomas Parker [88.6.19(h) Spake] (Box 18)
- Taussig Catalog # 102: 18th cent. MS accounts of an attorney 42 ff. [88.6.23 Smallwood & Randall] (Box 18)
- Taussig Catalog # 103: 1864 (7 June) MS retained draft of letter from Sir William Erle to anonymous peer (Misc. 103) [88.8.22 Spake] (Box 18)
- Taussig Catalog # 104: 17th cent. MS book recording expenses of lawsuit, 51 ff. [88.8.30 Block], 3 (Box 18)
- Taussig Catalog # 105: 20th cent. (1901) printed order completed in MS by Lord Halsbury postponing judge's sitting [88.10.18(a) Spake] (Box 18)
- Taussig Catalog # 106: 17th cent. (1683) MS power of attorney to receive salary of Sir Cresswell Levinz [89.1.17(a) Bristow] (Box 18)
- Taussig Catalog # 107: 19th cent. (c. 1800) MS essay on office of notary, 327 pp. [89.2.17 Alan Brett] (Box 18)
- Taussig Catalog # 108: 18th cent. (c. 1727) MS reports of cases 1723-7, probably by William Taylor, 309 pp. [89.3.31(a) Spake] (Box 18)
- Taussig Catalog # 109: 19th cent. (1815) MS case with opinion of Charles Abbott [89.3.31(b) Spake] (Box 18)
- Taussig Catalog # 110: 18th cent. (1789) MS case with opinion of counsel and ALS of Thomas Erskine, 3 pp. [89.3.31(c) Spake] (Box 18)
- Taussig Catalog # 110.1: 17th cent. (c. 1680/1) MS version of text printed as Triumphs of justice over corrupt judges, pp. 3-46 [89.5.11 Lawrence Shaw Antiques] (Box 18)
- Taussig Catalog # 111: 1866 (30 Oct.) ALS Lord Brougham to James Watts (Misc. 105) [89.5.24(a) Bristow] (Box 20)
- Taussig Catalog # 112: 19th cent. (1876-9) series of 45 ALS from Arthur Dunn Gardner to his father (Misc. 111) [89.5.24(b) Bristow] (Box 20)
- Taussig Catalog # 113: 18th cent. British Merlin1743 (printed), interleaved and annotated by Henry Hall with lists of his fees [89.9.26 Bristow] (Box 20)
- Taussig Catalog # 114: 19th cent. (1860-1901) MS and printed group of papers relating to career of Sir John Rigby [89.10.28 Mayfly] (Box 20)
- Taussig Catalog # 115: 19th cent. (1839) articles of association in Cheshire for prosecution of felons, 2 sh. [89.11.8 Knowles] (Box 20)
- Taussig Catalog # 116: 1867 (27 Dec.) ALS from John Duke Coleridge re: duties of counsel (Misc. 106) [89.11.23 W. Myers] (Box 20)
- Taussig Catalog # 117: 17th cent. MS account of proceedings in Parliament of 1628, 233 ff. [89.12.15 Sotheby's] (Box 21 (Oversize))
- Taussig Catalog # 118: 19th cent. (?1834/5) ALS from James Parke to Henry Goulbourn (Misc. 89) [89.12.21(b) W. Myers] (Box 20)
- Taussig Catalog # 119: 19th cent. (1824-34) MS attorney's ledger, 316 pp. [90.6.7 Wyatt] (Box 20)
- Taussig Catalog # 120: 1789 (4, 15 and 22 Aug.) three ALS from William Grenville re: riots (Misc. 38) [90.6.11 Bristow], 3 (Box 20)
- Taussig Catalog # 121: 18-19th cent (1799-1805) MS attorney's account, 92 pp. [90.6.11(c) Bristow] (Box 20)
- Taussig Catalog # 122: 17th cent. (1690) printed form of petition for release from prison completed in MS, 1 p. [90.9.17 W.H. Collectables] (Box 20)
- Taussig Catalog # 123: 19th cent. (1813) MS case and opinion of Sir Samuel Romilly, 1 p. [90.9.18 Spake] (Box 20)
- Taussig Catalog # 124: 17th cent. (1660) MS warrant to chief constables to search for rogues, Osgoldcross, Yorkshire, 1 p. [90.10.15 Knowles] (Box 20)
- Taussig Catalog # 125: 18th cent. (1782) MS appointment of John Ward as steward to Earl of Ailesbury, 1 p. [90.10.24(a) Bristow] (Box 20)
- Taussig Catalog # 126: 17th cent. (c. 1600) MS bill of costs in respect of common recovery, 1 p. [90.10.24(b) Bristow] (Box 20)
- Taussig Catalog # 127: 19th cent. (?1850) ALS from Frederick Thesiger to Mr Gurney, 3 pp. (Misc. 101) [90.11.5 Campbell] (Box 20)
- Taussig Catalog # 128: 19th cent. (c. 1822) ALS from Thomas Denman to Mr Dwarris, 4 pp. (Misc. 74) [90.11.13(a) W. Myers] (Box 20)
- Taussig Catalog # 129: 1796 (7 Dec.) ALS from Thomas Erskine to James Perry, 1 p. (Misc. 42) [90.11.13(b) W. Myers] (Box 20)
- Taussig Catalog # 130: 1889 ALS from Sir Charles Russell to Mr Justice Stephen, 1 p. (Misc. 113) [90.11.13(c) W. Myers] (Box 20)
- Taussig Catalog # 131: 1781 (24 and 31 Mar.) 2 ALS from Charles Bill to John Ward [90.11.21 Bristow] (Box 20)
- Taussig Catalog # 132: 1865 (20 Aug.) ALS from Sir Alexander Cockburn to Lord St. Leonards, 4 pp. (Misc. 108) [90.12.9(a) Spake] (Box 20)
- Taussig Catalog # 133: 1828 (6 May) ALS from Lord Eldon, 3 pp. (Misc. 77) [90.12.9(b) Spake] (Box 20)
- Taussig Catalog # 134: 17th cent. MS proceedings in Parliament Feb.-Mar. 1628/9, 6 ff. [91.1.30(a) Dupre] (Box 20)
- Taussig Catalog # 135: 19th cent. (2 Apr. 1829) MS opinion of John Dodson [91.1.30(b) Dupre] (Box 20)
- Taussig Catalog # 136: 1783 (1 Mar.) ALS from George III to Lord Thurlow re: appointment of Wiliam Jones as judge in India, 1 p. (Thu2) [91.4.15(a) Bonhams] (Box 20)
- Taussig Catalog # 137: 18th cent. MS two draft letters from Lord Thurlow concerning regency bill, 2 + 2 pp. (Thu3-4) [91.4.15(b-c) Bonhams] (Box 20)
- Taussig Catalog # 138: 1792 (6 May) ALS from William Pitt to Lord Thurlow re: Thurlow's office, 1 sh. (Thu7) [91.4.15(d) Bonhams] (Box 20)
- Taussig Catalog # 139: 18th cent. (1769) MS account of cash paid for counsel's fees, 4 pp. [91.5.18(a) Spake] (Box 20)
- Taussig Catalog # 140: 17th cent. (c. 1686) MS report of proceedings in Bishop of London's case, 12 pp. [91.6.3 Bristow] (Box 20)
- Taussig Catalog # 141: 1940 and 1943 2 ALS (i) from Norman Birkett to F.D.Mckinnon and (ii) from Mckinnon to J.W.Morris in On Circuit 1940 (printed) by Mckinnon (Misc123-4) [91.7.1 J. Rees] (Box 20)
- Taussig Catalog # 142: 18th cent. (1735) MS order to sheriffs of London to deliver felon's body for dissection, 4 pp. [91.9.30 W.H. Collectables] (Box 20)
- Taussig Catalog # 143: 17th cent. (c. 1661) legal commonplace, 320 ff. [91.10.13(a) Spake] (Box 22 (Oversize))
- Taussig Catalog # 144: 18th cent. MS report on a patent signed by Edward Thurlow, 4 pp. [91.10.13(b) Frances] (Box 20)
- Taussig Catalog # 145: G.W. Keeton, Shakespeare and his legal problems1930 (printed), with MS revisions by Keeton [91.11.14(b) J. Rees] (Box 20)
- Taussig Catalog # 146: 18th cent. MS draft letter by Edward Thurlow on regency bill, 3 pp. (Thu5) [91.12.14 Dupre] (Box 20)
- Taussig Catalog # 146.1: 17th cent. (1668) MS copy of opinion of Robert Stevens on foreign-built ships, 3 pp. [92.4.6 Dupre] (Box 20)
- Taussig Catalog # 147: 19th cent. (7 June 1820) MS opinion of Lancelot Shadwell, 1 p. [92.4.21(a) Quaritch] (Box 20)